dorma.com 2018-06-04

# DORMA Legals & Privacy | Privacy Statement

DORMA ("DORMA" including Modernfold, Inc., Rutherford Int'l Corp.) is committed to protecting your privacy.  This Privacy Policy discloses how we collect, share, and use information about you that DORMA collects through the [www.dorma-usa.com](http://www.dorma-usa.com/) | [www.dorma.com/us](http://www.dorma.com/us) (also [www.modernfold.com](http://www.modernfold.com/), [www.rutherfordcontrols.com](http://www.rutherfordcontrols.com/)) website and our use of and your ability to correct the information collected. The www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website provides visitors with information about DORMA and our products.  In using and viewing the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ website, you understand that DORMA may use your “Personally Identifiable Information” (such as name, email address, street address, or telephone number) subject to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

##### Information Collected on the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website

The majority of the information provided by DORMA on the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website is available without DORMA collecting any Personally Identifiable Information from you and you can review almost the entire www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website without disclosing any Personally Identifiable Information.  However, DORMA does collect Personally Identifiable Information that you may voluntarily provide to us.  Some examples of times when DORMA collects Personally Identifiable Information include when you:

  * Submit an online request for information about DORMA
  * Ask DORMA about employment opportunities and send us your resume or other employment experience information
  * Submit an on-line application for employment
  * Complete a survey
  * Register for a promotion, or
  * Send us an e-mail message

You have a choice as to whether to provide DORMA with any Personally Identifiable Information.  Although you are not required to disclose any Personally Identifiable Information to us, portions of the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website may not be available to you without your providing this information.

Due to the business-oriented nature of our business and the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website, the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website is not designed to appeal to children under the age of 13. We do not knowingly request or receive any information from children.

##### How We Use Your Information

DORMA uses any Personally Identifiable Information you provide in a limited number of ways.  We may use your Personally Identifiable Information to (i) provide you with information about DORMA and its products and employment opportunities with DORMA, (ii) enhance or update the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website; (iii) review your account to determine whether other DORMA products may be of interest to you; (iv) conduct a transaction that you have requested; and (v) compile demographic statistics about our users.  We may also on occasion combine information about you that we have with information we obtain from other parties to enhance our ability to market to you those products that may be of interest to you.

In addition, DORMA may hire other companies to perform services on our behalf such as operating certain aspects of the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website or sending you email.  These other companies may be supplied with or have access to your Personally Identifiable Information for the sole purpose of providing these services to us or on our behalf.   DORMA may also use third-party ad servers or ad networks to deliver ads to you on DORMA’s behalf.  These third-party ad servers may be supplied with or have access to your Personally Identifiable Information for the sole purpose of providing these services to us or on our behalf.  They also may also collect and use non-personally identifiable information about your visits to the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website in order to send advertisements that may be of interest to you.

Though we will make every effort to preserve user privacy, we may need to disclose Personally Identifiable Information when required by law or if we have a good-faith belief that the action is necessary to comply with a pending judicial proceeding, a court order or legal process served on DORMA or to protect our rights or the rights of others, to fight fraud, identity theft, to ensure the integrity and operation of our business and systems, or to protect the rights, property or safety of DORMA, its employees, members or others.

##### How We Share Your Information

We will not disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to others without your permission, except as explained in this Privacy Policy.

##### Third Party Offers

In arranging to have marketing and promotional information of third party companies that we think might be of interest to you, we may disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to nonaffiliated third parties not controlled by DORMA.  If you do not want to us to disclose your Personally Identifiable Information to third party companies, simply send us an email at privacy@dorma.com as described in the section below on Accessing and Updating Information.

##### Aggregate Information

On an aggregate basis only, we collect comprehensive demographic, business information and data, and other non-identifying information about users of the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website.  DORMA will never disclose any Personally Identifiable Information as part of this aggregate information but we may lend, sell, share or otherwise disclose aggregate information with others so we can perform research and provide the results to third parties, enhance and market the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website, and conduct accounting and process record keeping functions.

##### Other websites and links

We may include links to other websites that we think will be of interest to you or operated by our business partners, affiliates, advertisers, and others. These third parties have separate data collection and privacy practices independent from ours, and DORMA cannot be responsible for their policies or activities. Please contact those third parties directly if you have questions about their privacy policies.

##### Cookies, Web Beacons, Clear Gifs, and IP Addresses

DORMA also uses a feature of your browser called a “cookie.”  Your cookie automatically identifies your computer - but not you - to our servers when you visit the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website and allows us to correlate your computer with certain usage patterns which are stored in our log files.  We use cookies to gather general, aggregate statistics about the overall popularity and usage of www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website.  DORMA also uses more temporary cookies, often referred to as session cookies, to keep a user logged into the system and aid in the exchange of information between pages without loss of data.  Such a cookie, however, is only stored for the current browsing session and is deleted once the browser is closed. DORMA can also only read cookies from the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website.  Search for Cookies under your Web browser's Help menu for more information on cookie management features available to you.  If your browser is set to reject all cookies, the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website may not function properly.

DORMA may also collect information through the use of clear gifs (also called Web Beacons and Web Bugs) in selected email messages we send to you. These are tiny graphic files, not visible to the human eye, that are included in HTML-based emails and used to let us know which emails we send are opened.  Clear gifs may also see or read cookies on your computer.  When authorized by DORMA, third parties specializing in monitoring aggregate statistical use of our site with whom we contract, may use cookies, our web log files, web beacons, and other monitoring technologies to compile anonymous aggregate data.

Additionally, we may use IP address information to count and track aggregate visits to www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website, to help diagnose problems with our server, and to administer the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website.  DORMA does not link IP addresses to anything personally identifiable so while a particular user’s session can be tracked, the user remains completely anonymous.

##### Accessing and Updating Information

DORMA does not currently have an online method for users to delete their Personally Identifiable Information contained in our database. However, you may change or update the Personally Identifiable Information we have collected, request that we delete it, or request that we change how we use it by sending an email to privacy@dorma-usa.com with your instructions.

##### Changes to this Privacy Policy

We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy not just the first time you visit the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website but periodically afterwards since we may modify our Privacy Policy from time to time.  The date of the last update of the Privacy Policy will always be posted below:

THIS PRIVACY POLICY WAS LAST REVISED ON APRIL 1, 2005.

If we make any substantive changes to our Privacy Policy in the future with regard to how we use your Personally Identifiable Information, we will incorporate those changes here.  Your continued use of the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website after the changes are posted constitutes your agreement to the changes, both with regard to information we have previously collected from you and with regard to information we collect from you in the future. If you do not agree to the changes, please discontinue use of the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website.  Lastly, if DORMA is sold or merged with another company, your Personally Identifiable Information will be included as part of the sale but unless you’re notified that the Privacy Policy is changed, your Personally Identifiable Information will be maintained in the same manner.

##### International Users

Like almost every website, the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website is accessible around the world.  By visiting the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website and providing your information, you acknowledge and agree that your personal information can be stored for the purposes identified in this Privacy Policy.  We process and store your information in North America and your information may be stored on servers located outside your residential jurisdiction and which may have less stringent privacy practices than your own.  If you access the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website from outside the United States, your usage of the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website constitutes consent to the transfer of your data outside of your country and to North America.

##### Security

This Website has industry-standard security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse, and alteration of the information under our control, and we make good faith efforts to store your personal information in a secure operating environment. Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be absolutely secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, we cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk.  If DORMA provides you with a user name and password to access other portions of the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website, DORMA disclaims any responsibility for a breach of privacy as a result of your willingly or inadvertently disclosing your user name and password to others.

##### Contacting DORMA

Please feel free to share any comments and concerns with us. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy or the practices of the www.dorma-usa.com | www.dorma.com/us/ Website, please contact us at:

DORMA USA, Inc.  
Dorma Drive, Drawer AC  
Reamstown, PA 17567-0411  
Attention:  Privacy Manager

Or by e-mail at: [privacy@dorma-usa.com](mailto:privacy@dorma-usa.com)

**A.     Information regarding the collection of personal data**

(1)   In the following, we provide information regarding the collection of personal data when using our website. Personal data is defined as all data that relates to you personally, e.g. name, address, e-mail addresses, user behavior.

(2)   Controller in accordance with article 4(7) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) is

dormakaba International Holding GmbH  
DORMA Platz 1  
58256 Ennepetal, Germany

Our data protection officer can be contacted at [data.protection@dormakaba.com](mailto:data.protection@dormakaba.com) or using our postal address and adding "The data protection officer".

(3)   When contacting us by e-mail or using a contact form, the data you supply (your e-mail address, your name and phone number if necessary) are stored by us in order to answer your questions. We delete the data gathered in this regard once storage of such data is no longer required, or limit processing of such data should statutory storage obligations apply.

(4)   Should we require contracted providers to carry out individual functions of our offering or should we like to use your data for commercial purposes, we shall inform you in detail of the respective actions. In doing so, we shall also inform you of the defined criteria regarding duration of storage.

 **B.     Your rights**

You have the following rights vis-à-vis ourselves with regard to your personal data:

  * Right of access
  * Right to rectification or erasure
  * Right to limitation of processing
  * Right to object to processing
  * Right to data portability.

**C.     Collection of personal data when visiting our website**

(1)   When using our website for purely informational purposes, i.e. without registering or otherwise submitting information to us, we only collect the personal data that your browser transmits to our server. If you would like to view our website, we collect the following data that we require from a technical point of view to display our website to you and guarantee stability and security (the legal basis here is article 6(1) sentence 1, lit. f GDPR):

  * IP address
  * Date and time of enquiry
  * Time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)
  * Content of request (specific page)
  * Access status/HTTP status code
  * Volume of data transmitted
  * Website from which the request originated
  * Browser
  * Operating system and its interface
  * Language and version of browser software.

(2)   In addition to the aforementioned data, when using our website, cookies will be stored on your computer. Cookies are small text files stored on your hard drive by the web browser you are using, enabling certain information to be collected by the website owner who sets the cookie (in this case us). Cookies cannot execute programs or transmit viruses onto your computer. They are designed to make the internet service as a whole more user-friendly and effective.

(3)   Use of cookies:

a)    This website uses the following types of cookies, the scope and functioning of which shall be described below:

  * Transient cookies (b)
  * Persistent cookies (c).

b)    Transient cookies are automatically deleted when you close the browser. These include session cookies in particular. They store a so-called session ID with which the various requests from your browser are assigned to the session as a whole. This means your computer can be recognized when you return to our website. The session cookies are deleted when you log out or close the browser.

c)    Persistent cookies are deleted automatically after a specified length of time, which may differ depending on the cookie. You can delete the cookies at any time in your browser’s security settings.

d)    You can configure your browser settings according to your needs and decline acceptance of third-party cookies or all cookies, for example. We advise you that you may not be able to use all functions of this website.

e)    The Flash cookies used are not collected by your browser but by your Flash Plug-in. We also use HTML5 storage objects, which are stored on your terminal. These objects store the data required independently of your browser used and have no automatic expiry date. If you do not want Flash cookies to be processed, you have to install a corresponding add-on. The use of HTML5 storage objects may impede you as they use private mode in your browser. We also recommend manually deleting your cookies and browser history regularly.

f)    This website uses etracker Analytics, a web analysis service of etracker GmbH ("etracker"), and Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. ("Google").

 **D.    etracker Analytics**

(1)   The provider of this website uses the services of etracker GmbH, Hamburg, Germany ([www.etracker.com](http://www.etracker.com/)) to analyse usage data. Here, cookies are used which enable the statistical analysis of the use of this website by its visitors as well as the display of usage-relevant content or advertising. Cookies are small text files that are stored by the Internet browser on the user's device. etracker cookies do not contain any information that could identify a user.

(2)   The data generated with etracker is processed and stored by etracker solely in Germany by commission of the provider of this website and is thus subject to strict German and European data protection laws and standards.In this regard, etracker was checked, certified and awarded with the ePrivacyseal data protection seal of approval.

(3)   The data is processed on the legal basis of Art. 6 Section 1 lit f (legitimate interest) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Our legitimate interest is the optimization of our online offer and our website. As the privacy of our visitors is very important to us, etracker anonymizes the IP address as early as possible and converts login or device IDs into a unique key with which, however,no connection to any specific person can be made with. etracker does not use it for any other purpose, combine it with other data or pass it on to third parties.

(4)   You can object to the outlined data processing at any time provided it is related to your person. Your objection has no detrimental consequences for you.

 **E.     Google Analytics**

(1)   Google Analytics uses so-called "cookies", text files that are stored on your computer and enable analyses to be carried out regarding your use of the website. The information generated by the cookie about your use of this website is generally transmitted to a server of Google in the USA and stored there. In the event that IP anonymization is activated on this website, your IP address will be shortened in advance by Google, however, within Member States of the European Union or in other Contracting States to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be transmitted to a server of Google in the USA and shortened there. On behalf of the operator of this website, Google shall use this information to analyze your use of the website to compile reports on website activity and perform further services associated with website usage and internet usage for the website operator.

(2)   You can prevent cookies being stored by selecting the corresponding setting in your browser software; we advise, however, that you may not be able to use the functionality of this website to its fullest extent in this case. You may also prevent the gathering of data generated by the cookie relating to your use of the website (including your IP address) by Google as well as the processing of this data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

(3)   This website uses Google Analytics with the extension "_anonymizeIp()". Here, IP addresses are further processed in shortened form meaning individual identification of the user is not possible. Should the data gathered about you enable identification, this will be immediately precluded and the personal data immediately deleted.

(4)   We use Google Analytics to analyze and regularly improve use of our website. Using the statistics obtained, we can improve our offering and make it more interesting for you as a user. For exceptional cases in which personal data is transmitted to the USA, Google is subject to the EU-US Privacy Shield, <https://www.privacyshield.gov/EU-US-Framework>. The legal basis for use of Google Analytics is article 6(1) sentence 1, lit. f GDPR.

(5)   Third-party provider information: Google Dublin, Google Ireland Ltd., Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland, Fax: +353 (1) 436 1001. User conditions: <http://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html>, overview of data protection: <https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en>, and data privacy statement: [https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=en](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en&gl=en).
